A Guide to the Papers of the Secretary of the Board of Visitors of the University of Virginia, 1966-2000
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the Secretary of the Board of Visitors of the University of Virginia 1966-2000
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-1/2/1.001
This collection consists of ca. 15,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access
For ten years from the date of creation, access to these records will be granted only under the procedures of the Virginia Freedom of Information Act (Code of Virginia -2.1-340 ff.) or with the specific permission of the Secretary of the Board. Researchers interested in obtaining access to these records should direct a request in writing to the Office of the Legal Adviser, Madison Hall, University of Virginia.
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred by Jeanne F. Bailes, Clerk of the Board of Visitors, Office of the Board of Visitors, The Rotunda, University of Virginia on 2000 August 9.
Biographical/Historical Information
During the time span of these papers, Raymond C. Bice, Jr. (1969-1990) and Alexander G. Gilliam, Jr. (1991- ) both held the position of Secretary to the Board of Visitors.
Scope and Content Information
The papers consist of general records of the Secretary, including correspondence, memoranda, and related papers. Present is correspondence and materials related to affirmative action and the Qatar Project.
Contents List
- I: General Files
  - Adoption of an Interim Financing Resolution by Unanimous Consent of the Board 1983 (Box 1)
  - Accounting Operations 1985-1992 (Box 1)
  - Affirmative Action 1999, (4 folders) (Box 1)
  - Affirmative Action Letters 1999, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Alumni Association 1994-1999, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Association of Governing Boards 1993-1999, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Athletics 1995-1997 (Box 2)
  - Authorizing and Securing Dormitory System Revenue Bonds 1984 (Box 2)
  - Barrett, C. Waller 1970-1991 (Box 2)
  - Battle, John S., Jr. 1982-1997 (Box 2)
  - Board as Committee of the Whole 1994-1997 (Box 3)
  - Bond Anticipation Notes 1980 (Box 3)
  - Budget 1992-1995 (Box 3)
  - Bursar's Office 1990-1991 (Box 3)
  - Capital Campaign 1991-1996 (Box 3)
  - Certifications 1990-1996 (Box 3)
  - Clinch Valley College 1993-1999 (Box 3)
  - Clinch Valley College, Renaming of 1998-1999, (3 folders) (Box 4)
  - Coeducation 1968-1969, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - College of Arts and Sciences 1991 (Box 4)
  - Comments 1992 (Box 4)
  - Construction Cost Analysis 1989 (Box 4)
  - Development 1992-1996 (Box 5)
  - Dinner 1985 (Box 5)
  - Disclosure of Interests 1986-1987 (Box 5)
  - Dudley, Henry, A. 1983-1995 (Box 5)
  - Emergency Plan 1984-1986 (Box 5)
  - Endowment Fund Reserve Bonds 1982 (Box 5)
  - Executive Sessions 1995 (Box 5)
  - Facilities Master Plan-Final Draft 1989 (Box 5)
  - Faculty Housing Revenue Bonds 1972 (Box 6)
  - Fall Convocation 1994 (Box 6)
  - Faulconer, Hunter 1994-1998 (Box 6)
  - Final Pricing Information-Hospital Revenue Refunding Bonds (Series E) 1989 (Box 6)
  - Finals 1996 (Box 6)
  - Former Members of the Board 1996-1998 (Box 6)
  - Former Members of the Board, Pictures 1952-1962 (Box 6)
  - Founder's Day 1993 (Box 6)
  - Freedom of Information Act 1984-1993 (Box 6)
  - Friday Briefing Book 1995 (Box 6)
  - General 1994-1995 (Box 6)
  - General Counsel 1994-1998, (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - Gifts and Grants 1994-1997 (Box 7)
  - Governmental Relations 1967-1994, (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - Harrison, Albertis 1993-1995 (Box 7)
  - Harrison, J. Hartwell 1966-1984 (Box 7)
  - Health Sciences Center 1992-1999 (Box 7)
  - Human Resources 1981-1998 (Box 7)
  - Indenture 1982 (Box 7)
  - Indenture between the Rector and Visitors of U. Va. And Virginia 1972 (Box 7)
  - National Bank, Trustee
  - Institutional Profile for the Board of Visitors 1992 (Box 8)
  - Jefferson Scholar's Program 1997 (Box 8)
  - Johnson, Walkley, E. 1968-1986 (Box 8)
  - Kuykendall, J. Sloan 1964-1995 (Box 8)
  - Leggett, William E. 1972-1981 (Box 8)
  - Lewis, Lawrence, Jr. 1970-1995 (Box 8)
  - Manual 1947, 1960-1978 (Box 8)
  - Manual--Distribution List 1976 (Box 8)
  - Manual--Distribution of 1963-1975 (Box 8)
  - Manual Materials 1991-1996 (Box 9)
  - Manual--New Copy 1991 (Box 9)
  - Manual of Personnel Procedures 1968, (2 folders) (Box 9)
  - Mattern, Edward K. 1970-1982 (Box 9)
  - McCall, Howard W. 1974-1982, 1997 (Box 9)
  - McConnell, Joseph H. 1968-1992 (Box 9)
  - Medical School 1982-1992 (Box 9)
  - Meeting, Board 1993 (Box 10)
  - Meetings, Executive 1993-1996 (Box 10)
  - Meetings, Called 1990-1992 (Box 10)
  - Meetings, Full (1-3 of 8) 1996-1999 (Box 10)
  - Meetings, Full (5-8 of 8) 1996-1999 (Box 11)
  - Meetings, Full-Professorships 1997-1998, (3 folders) (Box 12)
  - Meetings, Open (1-3 of 12) 1989-1998 (Box 12)
  - Meetings, Open (4-8 of 12) 1989-1998 (Box 13)
  - Meetings, Open (9-12 of 12) 1989-1998 (Box 14)
  - Meetings, Preliminary 1995-1997 (Box 14)
  - Meetings, Regular (1 of 45) 1989-1966 (Box 14)
  - Meetings, Regular (2-4 of 45) 1989-1996 (Box 15)
  - Meetings, Regular (5-8 of 45) 1989-1996 (Box 16)
  - Meetings, Regular (9-13 of 45) 1989-1996 (Box 17)
  - Meetings, Regular (14-16 of 45) 1989-1996 (Box 18)
  - Meetings, Regular (17-19 of 45) 1989-1996 (Box 19)
  - Meetings, Regular (20-25 of 45) 1989-1996 (Box 20)
  - Meetings, Regular (26-30 of 45) 1989-1996 (Box 21)
  - Meetings, Regular (31-34 of 45) 1989-1996 (Box 22)
  - Meetings, Regular (35-38 of 45) 1989-1996 (Box 23)
  - Meetings, Regular (39-42 of 45) 1989-1996 (Box 24)
  - Meetings, Regular (43-45 of 45) 1989-1996 (Box 25)
  - Memoranda/Memorandum to the Board (1-5 of 13) 1994-1998 (Box 26)
  - Memoranda/Memorandum to the Board (6-11 of 13) 1994-1998 (Box 27)
  - Memoranda/Memorandum to the Board (12-13 of 13) 1994-1998 (Box 28)
  - Mingle, James J. 1988-1995 (Box 28)
  - Minutes 1974-1976, (2 folders) (Box 28)
  - Minutes-Correspondence 1993-1999 (Box 28)
  - Minutes, Excerpts from 1928-1999 (Box 28)
  - Minutes, Permanent Attachment 1984 (Box 29)
  - Miscellaneous 1996 (Box 29)
  - NCAA Self-Study Compliance Report 1995 (Box 29)
  - News clips (1-2 of 13) 1996-2000 (Box 29)
  - News clips (3-7 of 13) 1996-2000 (Box 30)
  - News clips (8-13 of 13) 1996-2000 (Box 31)
  - Notice of Sale 1987 (Box 32)
  - Nursing School 1988-1993 (Box 32)
  - Orator Universitarius 1993 (Box 32)
  - Palmer, George C., III 1974-1999 (Box 32)
  - Perry, Ferman W. 1980-1988 (Box 32)
  - Potter, William S. 1972-1981 (Box 32)
  - Professorships 1992-1995 (Box 32)
  - Purchase Contract 1972 (Box 32)
  - Purchasing 1995-1997 (Box 32)
  - Qatar 1997-2000, (2 folders) (Box 32)
  - Raven Society Re: Weldon Cooper 1979, (Photograph Album) (Box 32)
  - Remarketing Arrangement between the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia 1984 (Box 33)
  - Report of Inquiry Group on Virginia Student Aid Foundation (VSAF) Loans 1992 (Box 33)
  - Report on the Activities of the Appropriations Committee 1988-1989 (Box 33)
  - Resolution Re: Issuance and Sale of Endowment Fund 1982 (Box 33)
  - Resolution Re: Issuance of Bond Anticipation Notes 1980 (Box 33)
  - Retreat 1991 (Box 33)
  - Rogers, Frank W. 1966-1970 (Box 33)
  - Rogers, Frank Waters 1969-1982 (Box 33)
  - Saturday Briefing Book 1995 (Box 33)
  - Scott, Hugh 1971-1994 (Box 34)
  - Series Resolution Re: Authorizing and Securing Dormitory System (Floating Rate Demand) Revenue Bond 1984 (Box 34)
  - Slaughter, D. French, Jr. 1978-1998 (Box 34)
  - Standby Bond Purchase Agreement 1984 (Box 34)
  - Status of Women (Task Force) 1988 (Box 34)
  - Student Affairs 1986-1996 (Box 34)
  - Student Affairs and Athletics Committee Re: The Gay Student Union 1972 (Box 34)
  - Student Council 1987-1995 (Box 34)
  - Student Council's Academic Advising Report 1988 (Box 34)
  - Survey of University-Related Alumni Associations and Foundations 1972 (Box 34)
  - Talbott, Frank, Jr. 1970-1974 (Box 34)
  - Trinkle, James L. 1982-1995, (3 folders) (Box 35)
  - University Foundations 1992-1997 (Box 35)
  - University Property 1971-1975 (Box 35)
  - University of Virginia's Relationship with Construction Contractors and Design Professionals 1989 (Box 35)
  - Updike, Glenn B., Jr. 1979-1996 (Box 35)
  - Walker, Lewis M., Jr. 1962-1992 (Box 35)
  - Weaver, Edgar N. 1983-1997 (Box 36)
  - Wheatley, C. Stuart, Jr. 1968-1972 (Box 36)
  - White Burket Miller Center 1997 (Box 36)
  - Wilkinson, J. Harvie, Jr. 1966-1981 (Box 36)
  - Williams, Langbourne M. 1967-1994 (Box 36)
- II: Restricted Files (Box 37)